## Melissa Piper

I am a front-end developer with extensive experience developing for various industries, including higher education, nonprofits, service industries, and retail. I am an advocate for inclusiveness and accessibility throughout the web, and develop with the mindset that the internet is for everyone. I enjoy working on the subtle nuances that elevate a good website to a great website.

P: 412-377-5999

E: melissa.f.piper@gmail.com

W: melissapiper.com

in /in/melissapiper

## Experience

Aug 2018 - Present Elliance **Front-End Developer** I focus on developing and maintaining the front end of client websites, microsites and landing pages, paying close attention to usability and accessibility. Level Agency Aug 2017 - July 2018 **Senior Front-End Developer** I worked with RESTful API integrations with major CRM platforms, including Netsuite and Infusionsoft. I also updated and maintained existing client and internal websites using WordPress. As a senior developer, I provided project estimates and POVs. May 2014 - July 2017 **Beyond Spots & Dots Front-End Developer** I developed and maintained client and internal websites, primarily using Drupal. Most of my work focused on building new client websites, but I was also responsible for building and improving upon our custom-built internal project management system. **Branding Brand** Oct 2013 - Mar 2014 **Front-End Engineer** I worked on front-end customization of mobile-only e-commerce websites for major retailers across the United States. NuRelm June 2007 - Oct 2013 Web Production Specialist/Front-End Developer I developed websites for for-profit and non-profit organizations using open-source CMSes (Drupal, WordPress, Umbraco) for user-side content management. I focused on PSD to HTML, CSS, JSP, and Javascript theming and development. I also performed day-to-day maintenance and troubleshooting on current client and internal websites. Skills Shopify WordPress Drupal HTML CSS jQuery Javascript

## Education

SASS

JIRA

Git

Asana

Gulp.js

Basecamp

California University of Pennsylvania

**Graduate Certificate in Multimedia Technology Bachelor of Science in Applied Computer Science** 

Photoshop

a11y

REST

Sketch